José Emilio Pacheco Papers, circa 1940s-2010s: Finding Aid C1619
Manuscripts Division
- Correspondence, 1940-2010s; 10 boxes
  - Correspondence, circa 1980s; 5 folders (Box B-001294, Folder 1-5)
    Carpeta 2 - Cartas de: Luz del Amo, Eduardo Lizalde, Pablo Luis Ávila, Eleonora Delgado de Larrazábal, Jaime Labastida, Ángel Flores, Vicente Rojo, Albita Cama, Juan Ruiz de Torres, Roxana Patiño, Jorge Esquinca, Gloria Gervitz, Josef Haslinger, Marc Cheymol, Saúl Sosnowski, Ramón Aguirre Velázquez, Martha Paley Francescato, Mónica Acheroff, Armando Adame, Óscar Wong, Cinthya Steele, Julio Figueroa, Rubén Castillo, Héctor Eduardo Ciocchini, Hugo J. Verani, Frank Benett Gonzalez, José Durand, Rosa Elena Juárez y Ricardo Gómez, René Solís, Elizabeth Dora Umlas, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, José María Guelbenzu, Blanca García Monsiváis, Stephen Schlesinger, Naín Nómez, George McWhirter, Héctor Manjarréz, David William Foster, Magda Graniela-Rodríguez, Roberto Cantú, Joaquín Cárdenas, Dorothy Tanck de Estrada, Ricardo Aguilar, Josune García, Fermín Vargas Lázaro, Fernando Sánchez Mayans y Angela Torre de Sánchez, Guillermo Carnero, Richard D. Brecht, Wai-ming Wong, Kurt Neumann, Alicia Gómez-Navarro, Octavio Armand, Linda Carole Byrd, Jesús Quintero Mena, Lilia Márquez Balderas.
    Cartas a: Tomás Segovia, José Miguel Ullán, Vilma Fuentes, Fernando Benítez, Patricia Van Rhjin.
    Carpeta 3 - Cartas de: Guillermo Schavelzon, José Antonio Zambrano, Montserrat Ordoñez, Martha Canfield, José Ramón Medina, George McWhirter, Vilma Fuentes, Julio Figueroa, Efraín Kristal, Aziza Bennani, Paulino Pérez Sala, Rafael Cartagena, Magda Graniela-Rodríguez, Luis Porter, Hugo J. Verani, Encarna Abella, Emilio Carballido, Marco Antonio Campos, Katherine Silver, Peter Glassgold, Griselda Ohannessian, Porfirio Martinez Peñaloza, Elías Nandino, Fátima Fernández Christlieb, Cynthia Lee Ventura, Juan Ruiz de Torres, Jean Clarence Lambert, Alfonso García Cortez, Gérard de Cortanze, Alfonso Rodríguez, Cynthia K. Duncan, David Lagmanovich, Ofelia Ramírez, Randolph D. Pope, Alicia Borinsky, Luis Antonio de Villena, Michi Strausfeld, Robert G. Mead Jr., Celia Weller, Gustav Siebenmann, David Kossoff, Horacio Salazar Ortiz, John L. Bingham, Maureen Ahern, Konrad Schhaum, Álex Zisman, Beltrán Morales, Neus Espresate, Olga Feodoroff, Hubert Nyssen, Guadalupe Ortiz Elguea, Russel-Wood, Luis Sáinz de Medrano, Iván Silén, Carlos Olmos.
    Cartas a: Norma Klahn y Ruben Gonzalez, José María Guelbenzu, María Elena de Valdés y Mario J. Valdés, Silverio Cañada, Ana Clavel, Luz del Amo, Fernando del Paso, James Valender.
    Carpeta 4 - Cartas de: Luz del Amo, Armando Zárate, Mario Muchnik, Joan Seix Salvat, Carmen Claudin, Javier Barros, José Sole, Roberto Fernández Retamar, Salvador Olmos, Bárbara Bockus Aponte, Fátima Fernández Christlieb, Manuel Andújar, Raúl Morodo, Serge Zaitzeff, Abel Quezada, Stephen Schlesinger, Merlin H. Forster, Gerhard J. Fonken, Hazel M. King, George G. Wing, Luz Elena Zabala de Acevedo, Marianne de Gouvea, Joseph Vélez, Charles Perrone y Amelia Simpson, Yvone Yragui, John L. Brown, Olga Feodoroff, Juan José Barrientos, Ricardo Olivares Pineda, Jorge Ramírez Juárez, Russell M. Cluff, José Luis Barros Horcasitas, Tom Raworth, Katarzyna Krzemuska, Cindy Bisaillon, Rebecca Franco, Anne D. Kilmer, Joaquín Antonio Peñalosa, Kathy Escutia, Jorge Rodríguez Padrón, Álex Zisman, Enrique Pupo-Walker, Linda Scheer, Sabine R. Ulibarrí, Elías Nandino, Pierre Zekeli, Esther Tusquets, Ana Pizarro, Neus Espresate, Guillermo Sucre, Victoria Bridges, Cindy Steele, George McWhirter, Rubén Castillo, David A. Bary, Janet M. Livesey-McCauley, Silverio Cañada, Alfredo Romero Castilla, André Coyné, Juan Ruiz de Torres, José Luis Detta, Guillermina Fuentes Ibarra, Griselda Ohannessian.
    Cartas a: José Durand y Betty Ferber Aridjis.
    Carpeta 5 - Cartas de: Luz del Amo, Alfonso de María y Campos, Arturo Rico Bovio, Enrique Krauze, Saúl Sosnowski, Neus Espresate, Hugo Gutiérrez Vega, William D. Black, César Antonio Molina, Fernando Tola, José María Guelbenzu, Marielena Kolker, Nuria Galipienzo, Katherine Silver, Luis González-del-Valle, Rosario Santos, Javier González Rubio, Hugo J. Verani, Humberto Guzmán, Luisa Futoransky, Mario Muchnik, José Fernandes Fafe, José Miguel Ullán, Miguel de la Madrid Hurtado, Janet M. Livesey-McCauley, Elías Nandino, Julio Ortega, Carlos A. Solé, Peter Glassgold, Jorge Rodríguez Padrón, Gordon Brotherston, Salvador Mendiola, Fernando Sánchez Mayans, Luis Antonio de Villena, José Adán Castelar, Gerard de Cortanze, Elizabeth D. Kauffman, Luis Yáñez-Barnuevo, Marco Antonio Campos,, Sara Martínez de Graue, Fausto Vega y Gómez, Ángeles Solano, Russell M. Cluff, Greg Gatenby, Rafael Giménez Silés, Pedro Lastra, Guillermo Samperio, Armando Rojas Guardia, Antonio Tenorio Adame.
    Cartas a: Juan Gustavo Cobo Borda, Ángel Flores, Sidney E. Donell Jr., Nerissa Moran, Coral Bracho, Marcelo Uribe, José Antonio Pérez Porrúa, Trinidad Barrera, Jaime García Terrés, José Luis Martínez, Vilma Fuentes.
  - Correspondence, circa 1980s; 1 folder (Box B-001295, Folder 1)
    Cartas de: Thomas Hoeksema, Hugo J. Verani, Gordon Brotherston, Giancarlo Depetris, César Leante, Marcelo Uribe, Eduardo González, Carlos Ortiz Gil, José Luis Martínez, Otto Granados Roldán, Deborah J. Cohen, José Durand, Arthur Askins, Tino Villanueva, Enrique Verástegui, Marco Antonio Gil M., Federico Reyes Heroles, Guillermo Carnero, Randolph D. Pope, Alfredo A. Roggiano, Klaus Meyer-Minnemann, Tom Raworth, Pilar Saro, George McWhirter, Roberto Cantú, Julio Ortega, Vicente Rojo, Ilan Stavans, Janet M. Livesey-McCauley, Miguel Ángel Flores, Steven White, Allen W. Phillips, Salvador Pons, Francisco Hernández, Pere Gimferrer, Raúl Dorra, Roberto Fernández Retamar, Ana Duncan, Javier Pradera, Enrique Cortázar, Luis Antonio de Villena, Margo Glantz, Joseph F. Click, José Donoso, Carlos Vásquez Zawadski, Jorge A. Treviño Martínez, Neus Espresate, Stephen Schlesinger, Beatriz Garza Cuarón, Ricardo Aguilar, Claudio Giaconi, Félix Suárez, Enrique Florescano, Severo Salles de Albuquerque, Kathryn Karam, Saúl Sosnowski, Cynthia Lee, Jorge de Bengoechea, Celia Richmond Weller, José Kozer, Consuelo Velázquez, Teresa Méndez-Faith, Eduardo Lizalde, Dolores Martin, Christopher Murray, Esther Tusquets, Jiro Shibasaki, Takashi Ikeda, Jesús Kumate Rodríguez, Fernando González Gortázar, Rosa Jaramillo, Claudia Bum de Barberi, Herlinda Hernández, Bárbara Häusbinger, Carlos A. Solé, John M. Fein, Miguel Riera, Trinidad Barrera.
    Cartas a: Alejandro Moreno, Julio Figueroa, Silverio Cañada y María Calogne, Merlin H. Forster, Saúl Sosnowski.
  - Correspondence, circa 1990s; 4 folders (Box B-001295, Folder 2-5)
    Carpeta 2 - Cartas de: Arcadio Díaz-Quiñones, Peter T. Johnson, Jesús Ancer Rodríguez, Peter G. Earle, Vicente Rojo, Fernando Burgos, Anamari Gomís, Guadalupe García Barragán, Marcelo Uribe, Silvia Garza Garza, Jorge Alberto Moch Zamora, Mario Szichman, Ernesto Hereje Cornejo, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, Petch Peden, Juvenal Acosta, Pedro Lastra, Fernando Rabelo Ruiz de la Peña, Manuel Cosío, Vicente Quirarte, Verónica Grossí, Pablo Brescia, Juan B. Avalle-Arce, Víctor F. Freixanes, Mario Muchnik, Mónica Tusell, Fernando Degiovanni, Enrique Florescano, Bernardo Ruiz, Gaspar Aguilera Díaz, Carla Zarebska, Gordon Brotherston, Verity Smith, John S. Brushwood, Rodolfo Guzmán M., Ramón Layera, Miguel Felipe Sosa, Susan E. Garfield, Gabriela de la Vega, Sergio Mansilla, Graciela Uequín, Robert Quinn, Fabio Rodríguez Amaya, Carlos Álvarez-Ude, Juan Luis Campos, Elías Nandino, Habib Succar Guzmán, Abraham Nuncio.
    Cartas a: Alfonso de María y Campos, Francisco Montes de Oca, Ángela García, Aurora Díez-Canedo Flores, Elaine Katzenberg, María Montero.
    Carpeta 3 - Cartas de: Ignacio Durán Loera, Jorge Aguilar-Mora, Nelson Osorio, John Fitzpatrick, Patricio Tapia Pezo, Pedro Ángel Palou, Chila B. Hidalgo, Juan Manuel Sepúlveda, Héctor Aguilar Camín, Jayne Booth, Elizabeth McCleary, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, Lilia Márquez Balderas, Margarita Sierra y Maricarmen Canales, Jeanine Gaucher-Morales, Raúl Padilla López, Dante Medina, Juan Armando Epple, Delphine Delefosse, Luis Suñén, Katja Pitsounis, Juan Carlos Aguilera, Juan Carlos Rangel Cárdenas, Guillermo Soberón, Frederick G. Williams, Enrique Rodríguez Varela, Roberto Ferrnández Retamar, Fernando Burgos, Michael Doudoroff, Eugene McCarthy, Miriam Bertram, Sergio González Rodríguez, Wilberth Benoni López, Juan Luis Campos, John S. Brushwood, Joseph L. Vélez, George McWhirter, Eugenio Méndez, Florencia Lo Celso, Susana Valente, Lidia Morales, Jorge Isaías, Fernando Sánchez Mayans, George Plimpton, Aldred J. Mac Adam, Eduardo J. Padrón, Giorgio Vitale, Pierre Yves Souci y Catherine Daems, Petch Peden, Manolo F. Medina, Jennifer L. Comeau, Peter G. Earle, John Felstiner, Miriam Bautista y Athenea Vargas, Fernando Canales Lozano, Martha Paley Francescato y Guido, Juan Ruiz de Torres, Susana Beatriz Cella, Regina Igel, William E. Kriwan, Felipe Garrido.
    Cartas a: Saúl Sosnowski, Jorge Halperín, Andrew P. Debicki, Silvio Zavala, Diego López Rivera, Arturo Gutiérrez Plaza.
    Carpeta 4 - Cartas de: Enrique Pupo-Walker, Calude Fell, José Antonio Mazzotti, Alfonso Castillo Burgos, Yillian Castro Coppolechia, César Antonio Sotelo Gutiérrez, Fátima Fernández Christlieb, David Huerta, Francisco López Cámara, Ángel de la Vega Navarro, Roberto Fernández Retamar, Graciela Uequín, Karl Kirchwey, Melissa Hammerle, Miriam Bertram, José Luis Barros Horcasitas, Gonzalo Rojas, Vicente Rojo, Bernardo Ruiz, Magda Graniela-Rodríguez, Rafael Olea Franco, Beatriz Nava Rivera, Salvador Rocha Díaz, Beatriz Berger,, Jorge Cornejo Polar, Jürgen Siess, Eneas Caldiño, Madou Moulaert, Gail Fenderson, Salvor Galván Infante, Víctor F. Freixanes, Ida Vitale y Enrique Fierro, Carlos Ferrer, Douglas Messerli, Germán Gullón, Adela Pineda, Rafael Marín, Felipe García Beraza, José Luis Ontiveros Menéndez, Francisco Márquez Villanueva, Luis Rafael Sánchez, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, Mónica S. Giannone, Mario J. Valdés, Diane Pineda, Cynthia Steele, Sophie de la Calle.
    Cartas a: Marianna Archambault; Gerard de Cortanze, Saúl Sosnowski, Beatriz Berger.
    Carpeta 5 - Cartas de: Marcelo Uribe, Hugo J. Verani, Raúl Ortiz y Ortiz, Cynthia Steele, Amelia Mondragón, Jannette Castillo, Juan Carlos Moyano Ortiz, Anamari Gomís, Rocío Oviedo y Pérez de Tudela, Julia San Miguel Martos, Aurelio Major, Juan Armando Epple, David Curland, Julia y Carlos Pellicer López, Mercedes de la Garza Hernández, Rowena Torrevillas, Isabel Bastos, Saúl Sosnowski, Blanca Luz Pulido, Pablo Pacheco López, Jennifer L. Comeau, Laurietz Seda, Michael Doudoroff, Ramón Layera, Jorge Esquinca, Gail Fenderson, Carmen Gaitán, Bernardo Ruiz, Teresa Franco, Peter Boyle, Giorgio Vitale, Luis Villanueva, Isabel Schon, José Miguel Oviedo, Mary Docter, John Incledon, Arturo Trejo Villafuerte, Gaspar Aguilera Díaz, Santos López, Humberto Gamboa, Lilia Márquez Balderas, René Solís, Gerardo Estrada, Adela Pineda, John Lyons, Gerard de Cortanze, Patricio Chirinos Calero, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, Mario J. Valdés, Guillermo Michel, Eduardo Labarca, Ingrid Führer, Hernán Lara Zavala, José Gaxiola López.
    Cartas a: Frederick G. Williams, César Leante, Juan José Doñan, Javier Sanjines, Dennis Berenchot, Ernesto Zedillo Ponce de León, Jorge Cornejo Polar, Alfonso de María y Campos, Germán Araujo Mata, Osvaldo Sama, Daniel de la Fuente.
  - Correspondence, circa 1990s; 4 folders (Box B-001296, Folder 1-4)
    Carpeta 1 - Cartas de: Karla Berenice Alavez Cruz, Sophia James Tello, Miguel Ángel Castillo Pérez, Thanos Mikroutskikos, Rodrigo Moya, Javier González Rubio Iribarren, Fernando Benítez, Adolfo Castañón, Miriam Grunstein, Eva-Maria Willkop, Jaime García Terrés, Julio Derbéz del Pino, David Curland, Douglas Messerli, Guadalupe Zárate, John Dubouchet, Giorgio Vitale, Roberto Vázquez, Mario J. Valdés, Carlos Sánchez Lozano, Betsy Edgar, Mariano Flores Castro, Jorge Cornejo Polar, Freddy Domínguez Naréz, Jesús Quintero Mena, Francisco Márquez Villanueva, David Huerta, Fernando Burgos, Tom Raworth, Manuel Alonso Muñoz, Ricardo Azuaje, Roberto Fernández Retamar, George McWhirter, Susana Beatriz Cella, Margarito Cuellar, Juan Carlos Marset, Marcelo Uribe, Claudia Cadena Silva.
    Cartas a: Gabriel Pereyra, César Antonio Molina, Jorge Aguilar Mora, Irma López, Paloma Gorostiza, Ángela García y Fernando Rendón, Homero Gayosso Animas, Alberto Dallal, Armando Ponce, Ana María Morales y Miguel Sardiñas, Patricia Gregory.
    Carpeta 2 - Cartas de: Thanos Mikroutskikos, Luis Maldonado Venegas, Rodrigo Moya, Rafael Olea Franco, Mónica del Villar, Douglas Messerli, Carmen V. Vidaurre, Jorge Medina Viedas, Gordon Brotherston, Carmen Criado, Rafael Martínez Alés, Rebeca Barriga Villanueba, Juan José Barrientos, Saúl Sosnowski, Jorge Aguilar Mora, William E. Kirwan, Andrés Reséndez, Gregory L. Lamping, Eugenio Méndez, Lilia Márquez Balderas, Héctor Carreto, Jorge Carpizo, David Curland, Andrew P. Debicki, Giorgio Vitale, Jorge Valdés Díaz-Vélez, Juvenal Acosta, Susana Villalba, Álvaro Uribe, Benjamín Rocha, Anthony Cummings, Raúl G. Acosta, Judith Infante, Isabel Schon, Susan P. Pavliscak, Ilan Stavans, Annie Finch, Fernando Burgos, Juan García Ponce, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz (y Larissa Chaddick), Sergio González Rodríguez, María Alcibíades, Francisco Azuela, Tobias Burghardt, Miriam Bertram, Gerard de Cortanze, Roberto Fernández Retamar, Frank Dauster, José Antonio Yépes Azparrén, Lino García Jr.
    Cartas a: Fernando García Núñez, Antonio García-Lozada, Ana Laura Delgado, Juan Bautista Avalle-Arce, Aurora Díez-Canedo, Inés Azar, Fausto Vega, Armando Ponce, Rebeca Arzate, Marcelo Uribe, Mónica Herrera, Kathryn Birkhead, Martha Elene Venier.
    Carpeta 3 - Cartas de: Genaro Borrego E., Héctor Pérez-Rincón, Jesús Quintero Mena, Victor Hernández Cruz, Susana Chávez Silverman, Michael Sisson, Carlos Fuentes, Enrique Verástegui, Carlos Ortega G, Bernardo J. Ruiz López, Roberto Mazzanti, Paul Raymond Côté, Douglas Messerli, Sara Gerson, Luis Eyzaguirre, John Fitzpatrick, Carlos Cortínez, Saúl Ibargoyen, Pedro Lastra, Gerardo Cornejo, Larry B. Williams, Jr., Ana Laura Delgado R., Ramón Ojeda Mestre, Fernando Degiovanni, Margaret Sayers Peden, Pablo Narral, Gaspar Aguilera Díaz, James Davis, Peter Kardon, María Rosa Fiscal, René de Costa, Mario J. Valdés, Carla Zarebska, Lilia Márques Balderas, Isabel Fraire,Gastón Melo, Joseph Richey, Ramón Aupart Cisneros, Alfredo Baranda García, Alberto Betancourt, Miguel Ángel Zapata, Andrew Rothgery, Rafael Pérez Gay, Mauricio Maillé, Hans Meinke, Fernando Sánchez Mayans, Joel Weinstein, Raúl Vallejo, Jesús Guerrero, Ángel de la Vega Navarro, María Nadotti, Fernando Burgos, Isabel Schon.
    Cartas a: Javier Sanjines, René Solís, Alfonso García Quiñones, José Carreño Carlón, Arturo Ripstein, Sealtiel Alatriste, Daniel Dultzin, Peter Earle, Juan Villoro, Julio Bracho.
    Carpeta 4 - Cartas de: Enrique Krauze, Pedro Lastra, María Andrea Fernández Sepúlveda, Jorge Cornejo Polar, Fernando Burgos, Peter Kardon, Saúl Sosnowski, Robert Griffith, Ilene H. Nagel, Adele Berlin, William E. Kirwan, Antonio Saborit, Manolo F. Medina, Ana Wajszczuk, Rita A. M. Cooley, Manuel Durán, Mónica Mora Herrera, Steven White, Gabriela de la Vega, Carlos Bautista, Juan Armando Epple, Hugo Valdés M., Roberto Fernández Retamar, Parris N. Glendening, Mario J. Valdés, Patricia Cabrera, Roberto E. Wagner, Humberto Gamboa, María del Carmen Ruiz Castañeda, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, Leslie Bary, Gordon Brotherston, Vicente Quirarte, Enrique Verástegui, Enrique Florescano.
    Cartas a: Jorge Aguilar Mora, Adriana Valadez, Margaret Sayers Peden, Ignacio Fernández, René Solís, Ineke Phaf, Fernando de Toro, Hugo Gutiérrez Vega, Andra Zweifel, Juan Villoro, Thiago de Melo, Rafael Vargas, Fausto Vega, Héctor Orestes.
  - Correspondence, circa 2000s; 5 folders (Box B-001297, Folder 1-5)
    Carpeta 1 - Cartas de: Paulina Lavista y Salvador Elizondo, Juana Inés Abreu, María Cristina Cepeda, Miguel León-Portilla, Sari Bermúdez, Fernando del Moral, Morton A. Kaplan, Margarita Marco, José Luis Chea Urruela, Dyma Ezban, Charles Brower, Olga Correa Inostroza, Leopoldo Solís, R. Pinar, Félix Santos, Mónica Herrera, Saúl Sosnowski, Carmen Benito-Vessels, J. David Allen, George McWhirter, Linda Egan, Jorge Herralde, Vicente Quirarte, Teodoro González de León, Humberto Beck, Tino Villanueva, Cecilia Salmerón Tellechea, Álvaro Ruiz Abreu, Edith Negrín, Ignacio Solares, Luis Felipe Rodríguez, Juan Carlos Reyes, Giōrgos Rouvalēs, Jorge Lamoyi, Peter Kardon, JEP, Kosrof Chantikian, Julián Herbert, Mary Cruz Díaz Álvarez, Teresa Hernández-Vela Borja, César Bisso, Olga Feodoroff, Matthias Jäger, Jesús García Sánchez, Sergio Pitol, Pilar Gadea, Óscar Reynaldo Gonzales, Claudio Isaac, Paco Ignacio Taibo II.
    Cartas a: Omar Karamán, Luis Mier y Terán Casanieva, Armando Ponce, Mary Zetts, Adolfo Castañón, José Miguel Oviedo, Darío Jaramillo Agudelo, Martha Cantú, Hugo Gutiérrez Vega, Dinorah Basañez, Andrés Valdivia, Pennie Ojeda, Roberto Fernández Retamar, Gabriel Yáñez.
    Carpeta 2 - Cartas de: Ulrich Schreiber, Alicia Reyes, Alejandro Encinas Rodríguez, Carmen Caffarel Serra, Silvia Pastrana, Raúl Salinas de Gortari, José Miguel Delgado, Agnieszka Bolikowska, Pilar Gutiérrez, Lucinda Ruiz de Gutiérrez, Margaret Sayers Peden, Adhely Rivero, Héctor Orestes Aguilar Cabrera, Jorge Fernández Granados, Jorge F. Hernández, Carlos-Enrique Ruiz, Gerard Leman, Yanet Aguilar Sosa,Giōrgos Rouvalēs, Miguel-Angel Zapata, Francisca Noguerol, Alfonso Orejel Soria, Ignacio Echevarría, Adelina Plana, Rafael Olea Franco, Teresa Hernández-Vela Borja, Raúl Arias Lovillo, Clarice Smith, Juan Carlos Quintero-Herencia, Sandra Messinger Cypess, Marcelo Uribe, Edith Negrín, Ernesto Lumbreras, Enrique X. de Anda Alanís, Fausto Vega, Magdalena Trillo y Jorge Muñoz, Aurora M. Ocampo, Jesús García Sánchez, Inés Sáenz, Vicente Quirarte, Juan Manuel González Camarena, Carlos Fuentes, Fernando Burgos, Luis López Álvarez, Juan Domingo Argüelles, R. Pinar, Tobias Burghardt, Pablo Boullosa, David Huerta, Consuelo Sáizar.
    Cartas a: Alberto Bustani Adem, Sara Font Giner, Michael Long, Álvaro Mutis, Ron Friis, Carmen Benito Vessels.
    Carpeta 3 - Cartas de: Carmen Benito Vessels, Pablo Brodsky, Juan Camilo Sierra, Antonio Gálvez, Tino Villanueva, Francisco Noguerol, Rafael Rodríguez Castañeda, Jean-Louis Silvy, Raúl Arias Lovillo, Agustín del Moral, Joaquín Diéz-Canedo F, José Morales Orozco, Vicente Leñero, María José Toro Nozal, Lena Demartini, Jorge Eduardo Arellano, Tomás Segovia, Jaime Avilés, Ignacio Echevarría, Susana Kaluzynski, Héctor Orestes Aguilar Cabrera.
    Cartas a: Pol Popovic y Fidel Chávez, Yolanda González, Michelle Valentine, Darío Jaramillo Agudelo.
    Carpeta 4 - Cartas de: Evangelina Villarreal, Sari Bermúdez, Víctor A. Arredondo, Andrés Valdivia Zúñiga, Margarita Marco, Pablo Brodsky, Álvaro Enrigue, James F. Harris, Edith Negrín, Alejandro A. Sansores Cambranis, Carlos Osorio Granado, Margaret Sayers Peden, John Williams, Marco Antonio Aguilar Cortés, Jesús García Sánchez, Carmen Tejeria de Terrazas, Giōrgos Rouvalēs, Adolfo Castañón, Malena Mijares Fernández, Antonio García Lozada, Rosa Morros, Ignacio Echevarría, Amalia Iglesias, Charlene Merithew, Ulrich Schreiber, Carmen Ruiz Barrionuevo, Ana Laura Delgado, Asunción Ansorena, Anna María Rodríguez Arias, Ana López-Alonso Ortueta, Ramiro Arias Barriga, Robert Wechsler.
    Cartas a: Juan Carlos Quintero-Herencia, Saúl Sosnowski, Roberta Lavine, Sandra Messinger Cypess, Hernán Sánchez de Pinillos, Mónica Herrera, Consuelo Sáizar.
    Carpeta 5 - Cartas de: Roberta Z. Lavine, Michael Collier, Mónica Herrera, José María Naharro-Calderón, Ana López-Alonso Ortueta, Anna María Rodríguez Arias, Marco Antonio Campos, Carmen S. Pacheco, Sergio Raúl Arroyo García, Amos Segala, Teresa Lorenz, Carlos Mapes, Jesús Guerrero, Hugo Verani, María Cristina García Cepeda, Kurt Neumann, Juan Carlos Herández Cueva, Eduardo Cruz, Margaret Sayers Peden, César Güemes, José García-Velasco, Fernando Rocío Oviedo, Luis Suñén, Carlomagno Sol, Roberto Fernández Retamar, Fernando Valverde, Rafael Coll Moreno, Jennifer Clement, María José Bruña Bragado, Giōrgos Rouvalēs, Marcelo Uribe, José G. Moreno de Alba, Urlich Schreiber, Beatriz de Moura, Jeannette Clariond, David Ortiz Celestino, Maigne Jeanne, Felipe Calderón Hinojosa, César Nava Vázquez, Celina Elia Reyes Ruiz, "Emperatriz", Rose Corral, James Valender.
    Cartas a: Fausto Vega, Carmen Criado, Armando Ayala Anguiano, Jesús Kumate, José Ignacio Carbajal, Marcelo Uribe.
  - Correspondence, circa 2000s; 3 folders (Box B-001298, Folder 1-3)
    Carpeta 1 - Cartas de: Francisco Toledo, Fausto Vega, Vicente Cervera Salinas, Graciela Palau de Nemes, James F. Harris, Renata Eguez, Jesús García Sánchez, Kurt Neumann, Carmen Helena Ruzza, R. Pinar, Malena Mijares, Amos Segala, Mario Bellatin, Armando Roa Vial, Enzia Verduchi, Teresa Vicencio Álvarez, Jorge Valdés, Enrique Florescano, José Miguel Oviedo, Edith Negrín, Ignacio Echevarría, Susan R. Suleiman, José Antonio Mazzotti, Antonio García L., Virginia Medina Ávila, Leonel Alvarado, Alexander Sequén-Mónchez, Ricardo Valero, José María Rodríguez García, Javier Garciadiego, Pedro Ángel Palou, Rocío Oviedo, Pol Popovic, Luís González Tosar, Rafeal Olea Franco.
    Cartas a: Arcadio Poveda, Alicia Reyes, Gustavo Fierros.
    Carpeta 2 - Cartas de: Ulrich Schreiber, Julio Ortega, María Guadalupe García Barragán, Rose Corral, Rafael Olea Franco, Luz Elena Gutiérrez de Velasco Romo, Roger Santibañez, Ron Friis, Michael H. Long, Gustavo Fierros, Sandra Messinger Cypess, Helen Winder, Anna María Rodríguez-Arias, Francisca Noguerol, Marcelo Uribe, Adelina Plana, Eduardo Cruz, Gabriela Olmos, Beatriz de Moura, Jesús García Sánchez, Hugo Estenssoro, Vicente Fox Quesada, Alejandro Negrín, Juan Camilo Sierra, Raúl Vallejo, Raúl Arias Lovillo, Víctor A. Arredondo, Adriana Ortiz Laniz, Adhely Rivero, Adolfo Castañón, José García-Velasco, Belén Alarcó, Porfirio Thierry Muñoz Ledo, Alfonso Alegre Heitzmann, R. Pinar, Armando Ayala Anguiano, Jaime Siles, Jorge Enrique Adoum.
    Cartas a: Consuelo Zaizar, Peter Kandon, Sue Dickinson, Rolando J. Romero, Martí Soler, Arturo Chabolla, Mónica Herrera, Regino Díaz Redondo, Ignacio Echevarría, Fausto Vega.
    Carpeta 3 - Cartas de: Ulrich Schreiber, Alejandra Echazú Conitzer, Reni Marchevska, Piero Montebruno, R. Pinar, Mónica Herrera, Peter Beicken, Laura Demaria, Juan Carlos Quintero-Herencia, José María Naharro-Calderón, Christine Moritz, Michael H. Long, Rosa Morros, Guillermo Sheridan, Anna María Rodríguez-Arias, Ana López-Alonso Ortueta, Marta Sahagún de Fox, Vicente Fox Quesada, Francisca Noguerol, Ignacio Echevarría, Roman Buchelil, Rubén Castillo Gallego, Luis Rebaza-Soraluz, Alberto Santillán, Jesús García Sánchez, José Ignacio Padilla, Miguel Ángel Zapata, Alicia Gómez-Navarro, Margaret Sayers Peden, Óscar Neidecker-Gonzales, Julio Ortega, Abelardo Oquendo, James Valender, Malena Mijares, Joaquim de Montezuma Carvalho, Víctor A. Arredondo, Rodolfo Ortega Tenorio, José de Jesús Sampedro.
    Cartas a: Terri Mertz, Fausto Vega, Ulises Sánchez Segura, Yenny Navarrete, Carmen Criado.
  - Correspondence, circa 2010s; 2 folders (Box B-001298, Folder 4-5)